# **Denis Quaid**

Mobile Phone: 083 3147691 Email: <u>denisq91@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>denisquaid.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/denis-quaid

## **Summary:**

I am a results oriented and diligent iOS developer with five years experience in mobile development. I make it my goal to create applications with the user in mind, creating applications with a usable and intuitive user interface. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code along with good test coverage. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and better myself as I work in an industry that is subject to constant change and I am always open to new ideas and ways of working.

## Tools & Libraries:

I have experience with the following tools, libraries and languages:

**Languages:** Swift, Objective-C, Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Tools: Git (Github, Stash, Bitbucket, SourceTree), RxSwift, CocoaPods, Xcode, Testflight, Npm

**Continuous Integration**: Bitrise, GOCD, Travis

Libraries: UIKit,, AlamoFire, XCTest, Firebase, Core Data, Core Animation, Core Graphics, GCD

# Work Experience:

#### **Teamwork**

iOS Developer

(August 2017 - Present)

Teamwork.com are a SaaS company who provide a suite world-class individual products that can also work together to streamline the work involved in any business.

As part of the mobile team at Teamwork.com, my day to day work involves currently involves working as part of a team of developers, designers and stakeholders to deliver a brand new Projects app based on the principles of TDD, clean architecture and reactive programming.

This has demanded a different approach to development than I have experienced previously, in which the apps were already fully featured and released to the public. I am thankful to have been given the chance to create and work on an app from it's very inception, and really put my mark on some of the features of the app.

I look forward to the release date and am sure businesses and community teams alike will enjoy a lot of the great features available to teams in the Projects iOS app.

#### YOOX NET-A-PORTER

iOS Developer

Link: https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/net-a-porter-womens-luxury-designer-fashion/id318597939

As part of the NET-A-PORTER iOS team I worked within part of the mobile team to deliver features and bug fixes in line with the current roadmap. My primary achievements include:

- Inheriting a completely Objective-C based application with less than 20% test coverage, after two years on the team this was raised to 45% and the majority of the app was ported to Swift 3.
- Creating a contract test suite using the Jasmine framework (Javascript based) running nightly on a number of mac mini's to test important micro-services on which the app depended.
- Refactoring the previous analytics library in order to deliver a new library which conformed to the Customer Experience Digital Data Layer (CEDDL) which allows us to seamlessly port to different analytics providers. I also took on the role of analytics champion within my team which meant I was the first point of contact for all analytics related work.
- Delivering the first shoppable Apple TV application which was featured in Apple's Best of 2016. (https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/mr-porter/id481673241)

#### THE NET-A-PORTER GROUP

*Graduate Software Developer* 

(September 2014 - March 2015)

I began at Net-A-Porter as a graduate software developer where I worked within a front end web development team. I used this time to discover different software development languages and gain experience of working within an agile team of developers and testers. The languages I focused on were mainly Node.js and Java. My main responsibilities and achievements during this time include:

- Created an application to dynamically generate a number of sitemaps for different categories and product pages on the Mr Porter website using Node.js and Express.js
- Worked within an Agile team maintaining a legacy J2EE website using TDD and modern best practice principles.
- Wrote unit tests to contribute to the test suite within the team and being part of the release process as a manual tester.
- During this time I also completed a number of online courses in order to improve my knowledge of software design practices and different languages.

## **Education:**

BSC Social Science (2010-2013)

University College of Cork: Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)

MBS Electronic Business (2013-2014)

University College of Cork: Graduated with Second Class Honours Grade One (2.1)

References available on request